<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HackSoc</title>
    <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HackSoc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What they don&#39;t teach you in a tech degree.</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-11-11/</guid>
      <description>Ex Development Secretary Daniel Cordell joins us for a talk: What they don&amp;rsquo;t teach you at Harvard business school in a tech degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHLy Old Linux</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-11-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-11-09/</guid>
      <description>Peter and James have a play with some old-ass Linux CDs we found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Install Event</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-arch-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-arch-install/</guid>
      <description>Prepare your best heckles, as Jacob and Peter will be installing Arch Linux live at this event - what could possibly go wrong?
The event will take place in the Exchange LT3 lecture theatre on Jubilee Campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Café</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-28-prog-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-28-prog-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to our programming cafe events!
This is a much more laid back event than our workshops and talks, just rock up and work on a project, and speak to other people about their projects! We&amp;rsquo;ll be encouraging people to do a brief show and tell towards the end, and you may end up spotlit in our newsletter!
The event will take place in the Exchange Building C33 (provisionally, subject to room bookings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Raspberry Pi Robot Arm with .NET 5, Blazor and SignalR</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-26/</guid>
      <description>In this talk Pete Gallagher takes you through everything you need to build a robot arm with a Raspberry Pi, .NET 5 a Blazor App and SignalR.
We begin by talking about .NET 5 and seeing how easy it is to install .NET 5. Then we look through the various circuits and spin up a console application to explore how we can control the GPIO on the Pi. We see how the Servos are wired up and get the code in place to start moving our Raspberry pi based Robot Arm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Docker</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-21-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-21-docker/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use Docker with Peter in this workshop.
This serves as a follow up to his talk from the first introduction event.
A Linux laptop or virtual machine (Ubuntu or Debian is fine) is highly reccommended to follow along, especially as there are no computers in the room we&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Introduction to Linux</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-linux-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-linux-intro/</guid>
      <description>Come along to an introduction to Linux for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t used the operating system before.
This talk will cover several areas:
 What is Linux? Why would I use Linux? What makes Linux different from other operating systems? How do I get started with Linux? Common gotcha situations. How to find help?  The event will take place in the Exchange Building LT3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Café</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-14-prog-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-10-14-prog-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to our programming cafe events!
This is a much more laid back event than our workshops and talks, just rock up and work on a project, and speak to other people about their projects! We&amp;rsquo;ll be encouraging people to do a brief show and tell towards the end, and you may end up spotlit in our newsletter!
The event will take place in the Exchange Building C33 (provisionally, subject to room bookings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Discord Bots</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-discord-bot-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-discord-bot-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Come along to our first workshop of the year and learn how to make your own Discord bot using JavaScript!
Prior knowledge of JavaScript or programming in general isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary, as we&amp;rsquo;ll be explaining everything as we go along. We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the discord.js library, which will be the main focus of the workshop.
There&amp;rsquo;ll be a quick introduction to the discord.js library, and then you&amp;rsquo;re free to make whatever crazy idea you might have for a bot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Talks</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/awesome-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/awesome-talks/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Talks   A list of talks, curated by Hacksoc
Contents  Programming SysAdmin / Servers / Deployment Game Dev Open Source Community Cyber Security RF and Radio Low-Level &amp;amp; OS  Programming  https://youtu.be/QyJZzq0v7Z4 Why Isn&amp;rsquo;t Functional Programming the Norm? (Richard Feldman, Clojutre 2019) https://youtu.be/6hC9IxqdDDw This Videogame Programmer Used the STL and You Will Never Guess What Happened Next (Mathieu Ropert, CppCon 2019) https://youtu.be/IAdLwUXRUvg Non-conforming C++: the Secrets the Committee Is Hiding From You (Miro Knejp, CppCon 2019) https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Café</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-09-30-programming-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-09-30-programming-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to our first programming café of the year!
This is a much more laid back event than our workshops and talks, just rock up and work on a project, and speak to other people about their projects! We&amp;rsquo;ll be encouraging people to do a brief show-and-tell towards the end, and you may end up spotlit in our newsletter!
The event will take place in the A32 Ada Lovelace laboratory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Welcome Week Event</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-welcome-week-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-welcome-week-up/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to HackSoc! To kick off the new academic year, we&amp;rsquo;ve got our try-it introduction event. In this event, we&amp;rsquo;ll have talks on the following:
 Introduction to cyber security Asteroids to the Oscilloscope Coding for an art gallery  In addition to an overall introduction to the society, and an overview of how you can get involved in the wider Nottingham tech community.
The event will take place in the Keighton Auditorium, just down the hill from the Portland building, but will also be streamed on our YouTube channel because we may have to limit the number of people attending due to COVID rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Welcome Week Event</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-welcome-week-ju/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-welcome-week-ju/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to HackSoc! To kick off the new academic year, we&amp;rsquo;ve got our try-it introduction event. In this event, we&amp;rsquo;ll have talks on the following:
 Introduction to game development JPEG compression Docker &amp;amp; why it should be your friend  In addition to an overall introduction to the society, and an overview of how you can get involved in the wider Nottingham tech community.
The event will take place in the large Business School South lecture theatre on Jubilee Campus, but will also be streamed on our YouTube channel because we may have to limit the number of people attending due to COVID rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EGM</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-egm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/events/2021-egm/</guid>
      <description>Nominations for the remaining roles on the committee are now open, so be sure to nominate yourself if interested! On Tuesday the 13th of July at 7pm on our Discord we have an Extraordinary General Meeting (EGM) to fill out the roles on our committee. Make sure you come along to vote, and apply for a role if you are interested in contributing! If you want to run for committee yourself, please apply at https://hacksoc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EGM on the 13th of July!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-06-29/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    EGM on the 13th of July! Nominations for the remaining roles on the committee are now open, so be sure to nominate yourself if interested! EGM - Fill out your Next Committee! On Tuesday the 13th of July at 7pm on our Discord we have an Extraordinary General Meeting (EGM) to fill out the roles on our committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGM &amp; Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-04-28/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    AGM &amp;amp; Lightning Talks Coming up we have some lightning talks from our members, and our AGM is soon, on the 10th of May. Nominations for next year&#39;s committee are now open! Upcoming Events Our events run at 7pm and run on our Discord or via Zoom. For events running on Zoom you can join with the button below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computerphile, Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-03-30/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Computerphile, Hello World! Coming up tonight we have our last event of the term, a talk on the Computerphile YouTube channel from the people behind it. Upcoming Events Our events run at 7pm and run on our Discord or via Zoom. For events running on Zoom you can join with the button below.
Join on Zoom Computerphile, Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord Bot workshop, 3D printed bionics, and Computerphile talk!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-03-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-03-08/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Discord Bot workshop, 3D printed bionics, and Computerphile talk! Coming up we have a workshop on making modular discord bots in python, a talk on 3D printing prosthetics, and a talk on the Computerphile YouTube channel. Upcoming Events Our events run at 7pm and run on our Discord or via Zoom. For events running on Zoom you can join with the button below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging for Linux, Diversity Talk, &amp; More!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-02-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-02-22/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Packaging for Linux, Diversity Talk, &amp;amp; More! Coming up we have a workshop on packaging Linux applications, and talks on Diversity in Tech and 3D printing prosthetics. Upcoming Events Our events run at 7pm and run on our Discord or via Zoom. For events running on Zoom you can join with the button below.
Join on Zoom Packaging your application for Linux Workshop Tomorrow, on the 23rd of February at 7pm on Discord we have a workshop on packaging applications for distribution on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Back: Plain Text Talk &amp; More</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-02-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-02-01/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Welcome Back: Plain Text Talk &amp;amp; More Coming up we have a talk on the hidden story of text, and soon we have talks on JavaScript Game Development and Diversity in the Tech Industry. We hope you have had a good new year, and have survived your exams. Over the next term we have some great things to offer you, starting with an exciting selection of speakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automotive Cyber Security Talk and Final Fantasy Quirks</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-12-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-12-08/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Automotive Cyber Security Talk and Final Fantasy Quirks Coming up tonight we have a talk on Automotive Cyber Security, and to Thursday we have rescheduled our talk on the Quirks of the Final Fantasy games. Upcoming Events Our events run at 7pm and run on our Discord or via Zoom. For events running on Zoom you can join with the button below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code, Final Fantacy Quirks, and Automotive Cyber Security Talk</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-30/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Advent of Code, Final Fantacy Quirks, and Automotive Cyber Security Talk Thanks to everyone who attended HackNotts2020 over the weekend. Coming up in December we have a talk on the Quirks of the Final Fantasy games, and a talk on Automotive Cyber Security. Advent of Code In the run up to Christmas there is a series of programming challenged known as the Advent of Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Chance to get HackNotts Tickets!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-27/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Last Chance to get HackNotts Tickets! HackNotts is only a day away, so if you haven&#39;t already be sure to get your ticket! HackNotts: Get your ticket NOW! It&#39;s your last chance to get tickets to HackNotts, our fantastic Hackathon!
Tickets will remain available until the start of HackNotts on Saturday.
Find out more, and get your completely FREE ticket at the button below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackNotts is NEXT WEEK!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-23/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    HackNotts is NEXT WEEK! HackNotts is next week, so make sure you pick up your tickets! Coming up, on Tuesday we have drop in programming café, and we have plenty of great speaker events coming up as well. HACKNOTTS NEXT WEEK!!! HackNotts is NEXT WEEK, and we on committee are busy getting everything ready for HackSoc&#39;s greatest event of the year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackNotts in TWO WEEKS, Linux Workshop, and IoT Talk.</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2020-11-13/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    HackNotts in TWO WEEKS, Linux Workshop, and IoT Talk. HackNotts is just two weeks away, so make sure you pick up your tickets! Coming up, on Tuesday we have a workshop on getting started with Linux, and we have plent of great speaker events coming up as well. HackNotts - TWO WEEKS AWAY!!! HackNotts is JUST TWO WEEKS AWAY now, and we on committee are busy getting everything ready for HackSoc&#39;s greatest event of the year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding to Stack with .NET, Basic Game Development, and HackNotts soon!</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-11-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/newsletters/newsletter-2021-11-02/</guid>
      <description>HackSoc Newsletter  a:hover {text-decoration:underline} .button:hover {background-color:#007d32;text-decoration:none} .button:active {box-shadow:none;position:relative;top:1px}    Adding to Stack with .NET, Basic Game Development, and HackNotts soon! Tomorrow we have a talk on Adding to Slack with .NET. Next week we have a workshop on basic game dev in Monogame and HackNotts is getting very close, so make sure you pick up your tickets! HackNotts HackNotts is less than a month away now, and we on committee are busy getting everything ready for HackSoc&#39;s greatest event of the year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/archives/</guid>
      <description>archives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Committee</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/committee/</guid>
      <description>members of the committee</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hacksocnotts.co.uk/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
